Daniel A. Pinedo

Operations & Strategy Management

4 213.999.5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

SUMMARY

Manager specialized in people operations and business strategy. Experience in creating selection tools that incorporate machine-assisted decision-making. Leader that elicits focus, deep listening, and insights in colleague interactions. Background in research, evaluation, and statistical methods.

ABILITIES



Performance Monitoring & Evaluation



Coaching & Mentoring



Talent Research & Development



Talent Management



Nurturing Inclusive Culture



Operations & Strategy

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant

Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab

m 03/2019 - Current

Ownership of project deliverables and translation of research into business applications.

PROJECT 4: Creation of interview and validated scoring measure for culture fit interview

Research Associate

Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab

11/2018 - Promotion

Organizational behavior & evaluation research specialist.

- PROJECT 1: Statistical analysis for requirements of behavioral interview for future job candidates
- · PROJECT 2: Analysis of requirements for behavioral interview; initiated implementation plan with global management team
- PROJECT 3: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into pilot stage with global alignment teams

Team Lead

BCG Gamma Datathon

Invite-only case competition for BCG data analytics group among graduate students from USC Marshall, UCLA Anderson, and CGU Drucker management schools.

Managed ad-hoc cross-functional team of experts across three schools within Claremont Graduate University in the fields of artificial
intelligence, financial engineering, data science, management, organizational behavior, and organizational psychology.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

External Consultant

ICM Partners

1 09/2018 - 01/2019

% icmpartners.com

Project for large creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring.

• 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new hire.

Lecturer

Mount Saint Mary's University

m 01/2016 - 05/2018

% msmu.edu

Taught Research Methods, Social Psychology, and Organizational Psychology, with academic counseling.

Clinical Psychologist Intern

Sovereign Health Group

1 08/2014 - 08/2015

Inpatient facility with individual and group therapy, psychological assessment, and internal consulting services.

Assisted distribution of caseload to employees accounting for 25% increase in revenue and insurance billing.

EDUCATION

MA Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Claremont Graduate University

• Emphasis in Business Administration

MA Clinical Psychology

Sofia University

Palo Alto, CA

BA

Naropa University

Boulder, CO

SKILLS

Programming

R C+

C++

Python

LaTeX

Java

SKILLS

Statistics

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis